The Targeted Tailed Beast
(ガイ)風の国名物の大砂嵐か。
So this is the legendary sandstorm
of the Land of Wind!
(ガイ)噂には聞いていたが
すごいもんだな。
I'd heard rumors,
but this is mind-blowing!
(紅)二次試験を止めたのは正解ね。
Postponing the Second Exam
was wise.
Yes, one careless move
and you're dead.
(アスマ)ああ うかつに動けば死ぬ。
木ノ葉隠れの方々か。
Are you from the Hidden Leaf?
火影から風影様への書状を
預かっている。
We have a letter from Lady Hokage
to Lord Kazekage.
緊急の用件だ。
It's very urgent.
我々が届ける。
We'll deliver it to him.
風影様に 直接お渡しするように
と言われている。
Our instructions are
to deliver it to him in person.
通してもらえませんか？
Will you please let us through?
ならん。
No.
The Second Exam is under
the Sand's jurisdiction.
二次試験は
砂隠れに任されているはず。
That's unfortunate.
それは困った。
Well, since they won't let us through,
should we return to the Leaf Village?
でも 通してくれないのなら
木ノ葉に戻るとするか。
ああ… そうだな。
Yeah, I guess we should.
《２人とも下手な芝居を》
That's really bad acting, you two.
じゃ 失敬！
なに!?
Well, so long!
What?!
逃がすな！
Don't let them get away!
うっ… もう ダメだ…。
I can't take it anymore!
しっかりしろ！
砂漠のチリになるつもりか!?
Hang in there!
Do you want to rot in the desert?!
しかし…。
But…
うわっ!!
(カンクロウ)うろたえんじゃねえ！
Don't get flustered!
(カンクロウ)俺は砂隠れの監督官
カンクロウだ。
I'm Kankuro,
a Hidden Sand proctor.
お前たちを救出にきた。
I'm going to get you out of here.
カンクロウ様が わざわざ
助けにきてくださるとは…。
You came personally
to rescue us, Sir Kankuro?!
俺についてこい。
シェルターまで連れていってやる。
Follow me!
I'll take to you the shelter.
(みんな)はい！
– Yes, sir!
もうダメ… 歩けない。
I can't walk…any further.
えっ？
Listen to me!
(テマリ)いいか？ これも
中忍試験だと思って乗り越えろ。
Think of this as part of
the Second Exam and get through it!
監督官様！
Lady Proctor!
If you end up whining
over a mere sandstorm,
これくらいの砂嵐で
音を上げていたら→
砂隠れの里じゃ
中忍なんかになれやしないぞ！
you'll never make it
as a Sand chunin!
聞きしに勝るとは このことか。
Talk about exceeding
one's expectations…
I've never seen
a sandstorm this massive.
大砂嵐が これほどのものとは…。
息をするのもやっとね。
I can barely breathe…
任せなさい。 俺が止めてやる。
Leave it to me! I'll stop it.
Third Gate, Gate of Life…Open!
第三生門 開！
All right, follow me!
さぁ ついてこい！
うむ 行こう。
ええ。
Okay, let's go.
Yes.
(テンテン)ちょっと… 動かないでよ。
(リー)すみません。
Hey, stop moving around!
Sorry! But staying still is so stifling…
でも じっとしていると
息が詰まりそうで…。
このまま砂に埋もれてしまうなら
いっそ表に飛び出したほうが…。
Instead of getting buried
by the sand like this,
maybe we should make
a run for it…
(ネジ)待て。
Wait…
白眼！
Byakugan!
抜けた！
I broke through!
あと小一時間もすれば
砂嵐はおさまる。
The sandstorm should subside
in about an hour.
動くのは それからだ。
That's when we'll move.
わかりました。
I understand.
あと少しの辛抱ですね。
We just have to endure
a little bit more.
風影様に現状報告を。
I have a report on the situation
for Lord Kazekage.
よし 通れ。
You may enter.
入ります。
Excuse me, my lord.
We've received status reports
on the sandstorm from the teams.
各班より
砂嵐対策の報告が入っています。
現在 受験者たちは ほぼ全員→
Nearly all exam participants have
been evacuated to the shelter.
シェルターに避難していると
思われます。
ん？ 風影様？
Lord Kazekage?
何だ これは!?
What is this?!
どうした!?
What's wrong?!
お前たちの目は節穴か！
Are you men blind?!
砂分身…。
A-A Sand Clone!
風影様は どこにおられる！
Where is Lord Kazekage?!
(マツリ)ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much!
(我愛羅)
礼を言うなら 滝隠れのフウに。
If you thank anyone,
it should be Foo of
the Hidden Waterfall…
(マツリたち)はい。
行け。
– Y-Yes!
Now go!
二次試験も
じき再開されるだろう。
The Second Exam will
probably resume shortly.
Y-Yes!
(マツリ)はい。
♪♪(琵琶)
What?!
(ミコシ)何？
(ユカタ)敵？
An enemy?!
Where's it coming from…?
いったいどこから？
(ミコシ)コース選択を失敗したようです。
We chose the wrong route.
ここからでは
高台の様子がわかりませんね。
We can't see what's happening
on higher ground from here.
何 この音 気持悪い。
That sound gives me the creeps.
早くこのエリアから抜け出さなきゃ。
We should high tail it out of here.
Yeah, but let's proceed
with caution.
ええ 警戒しながら進みますよ。
♪♪(琵琶)
《ホウイチ : 法力 影法師》
Power of Dharma: Silhouette.
♪♪(琵琶)
(ミコシ)
テンポが 変わった。 急ぎましょう。
The tempo's changed.
Let's hurry.
(マツリ)そうね。
Yes.
♪♪(琵琶)
何！
えっ 影が。
What is this?
Huh?! The shadows…!
なんだ コイツら。
What are these things?
(ミコシ)うわ～っ！
(ユカタ)キャーッ！
♪♪(琵琶)
Sand Clone!
砂分身！
我愛羅様 これは？
Lord Gaara, what's going on?!
コイツらの狙いは 俺だ。
Their target is me.
お前たちが関わり合う必要はない。
There's no need for you
to get involved.
風影様が危ないとき戦うのは→
It's our duty as Sand Shinobi to fight
when our Kazekage is threatened!
砂隠れの忍としての義務です。
お前たちは二次試験に戻れ。
Return to the Second Exam.
それが砂隠れの忍としての義務だ。
That is your duty as Sand Shinobi!
《ホウイチ : 法力封印術！
Dharma Sealing Jutsu:
Sen no Rikyu!
仙除離吸！》
Get down!
伏せろ！
ううっ…。
I'm losing…my power…
《力が 抜けていく…》
The chain!
(マツリ)鎖を。
鎖を引き抜くのよ！
Let's pull out the chain!
(ユカタ/ミコシ)ああ！
– R-Right!
(マツリたち)うわっ！
行け ここは俺ひとりで。
Go! I can do this alone…
But…
でも…。
風影として命令する。
I order you as the Kazekage
to withdraw immediately!
速やかに
お前たちは ここから離脱。
このことは他言無用。 いいな？
And not a word of this
to anyone, understood?
(ユカタ)ねぇ どうすればいいの？
W-What'll we do?
How should I know?!
(ミコシ)そんなこと
俺にだってわからない。
Let's go to the central tower
and get help!
中央塔の本部へ。
助っ人を呼ぶの。
But…Lord Kazekage swore us
to secrecy!
でも 風影様は他言無用って。
You fool! His life is in danger!
バカ！ お命が危ないのよ！
Resistance is useless.
《抵抗も そこまでだ。
This is the sealing jutsu passed on
to me by Priest Bunpuku!
分福様から受け継ぎし封印術。
Now, I can extract Shukaku
from Gaara.
これより
守鶴を我愛羅から引き抜く！》
ううっ…。
ユカタ 大丈夫か？
Yukata! Are you all right?
I-I…can't move anymore.
もうダメ… 動けない。
マツリ ユカタは動けそうにない。
どうする？
Matsuri! Yukata can't go on!
What do we do?
ミコシ ユカタのことは頼む。
Mikoshi, take care of Yukata!
私が我愛羅様のことを
本部にお知らせしてくる。
I'm going to inform headquarters
about Lord Gaara!
しかし１人で…。
お願い 私は行く。
But, by yourself?!
Watch Yukata! I'm going!
マツリ…。
Matsuri…
♪♪(フウ)「100人の友ができるかな」
I wonder if I'm going to make
a hundred friends...?
(ヨウロウ)ったく あの気まぐれが！
She is so impulsive!
(ケゴン)中忍試験を放棄して
どうするつもりだ？
She's abandoning the Chunin Exams?
What is she up to?!
♪♪(琵琶)
ふぅ～。
やっと追いついた。
Foo…
We finally caught up…
(ケゴン/ヨウロウ)うわっ！
Where are you going, Foo?!
おい どこへ行くんだ フウ！
二次試験に戻るのか？
Are you going back
for the Second Exam?
うぅ… やはり読めない。
I just can't figure her out!
あっ！
待て！
– Hey!
– Wait!
せっかくできた同胞が
危ない目にあってるっす！
The friend I just made
is in trouble!
同胞？
Friend?
お前まさか 助けに行くつもりか？
もちろんっす。
Don't tell me
you're going to help?!
Of course!
戻ってこい フウ！
Come back, Foo!
Damn it!
クソーッ！
こうなったら二次試験は諦める。
Never mind
the Second Exam already!
アイツを無事に連れ戻せれば
それでいい。
We just have to
get her back safely!
あぁ…。
Y-Yeah…
ええい ここを通せ！
Hey! Let us pass!
火影から 風影様への書状である。
We have a letter for Lord Kazekage
from Lady Hokage!
預かる！
そうはいかんのだ！
We'll take it!
That won't do!
風影様に 直接お渡しする！
だから それはできんのだ。
We must deliver it
directly to Lord Kazekage.
I explained that's not possible!
こちらにはおられぬ。
He's not here!
こちらにも！
Not here either!
様子が変ね。
ああ。
Something's up.
Yeah… The Kazekage isn't here.
風影様は ここにはいない…。
なんとな！
What in the world?!
The Kazekage....?
風影が… うぅ…。
アハハハ…。
♪♪(琵琶)
うっ この鎖は…
チャクラが吸い取られていく…。
This chain…
is extracting my chakra…
《あれは!?
間違いない 尾獣チャクラ。
That's...!
There's no mistake.
That's Tailed Beast chakra!
このままじゃ
尾獣を抜かれて死んじゃうっす》
If left alone, his Tailed Beast
will be extracted…and he'll die!
《フウ…》
Foo!
来るな！
お前には関係ないことだ！
Stay away!
This has nothing to do with you.
アッシにも関係あるっす！
It does have something
to do with me!
わかってるっしょ？
アッシのこと。
You know about me…don't you?
Yes. You're a Jinchuriki too.
ああ お前も人柱力だな。
だから
アンタの苦しみはわかるっすよ。
That's why I can
feel your pain too.
苦しみを分かち合えるのが
友だって教えてくれたっす。
And you taught me that friends
understand each other's pain.
やめろ！
Stop it…!
うっ！
あぁ…。
力が吸い取られるっす。
It's sucking out my power…
大丈夫か!?
Are you all right?!
《もう１人いたのか。
So there's another one…
おもしろい。 分福様でも→
How interesting…
Not even Lord Bunpuku ever
sealed two Tailed Beasts at once.
尾獣２体を一気に
封印したことはあるまい。
法力封印の威力を
試すには絶好の機会》
This is the perfect opportunity to test
the power of the Dharma Seal.
♪♪(琵琶)
フウ 気をつけろ！
Foo! Be careful!
なっ!?
ああっ！
フウ！
Foo!
くっ… ごめん。
アッシ 失敗したみたいっす。
I-I'm sorry…
I think I failed…
《法力 仙除離吸》
Dharma Sealing Jutsu:
Sen no Rikyu!
♪♪(琵琶)
ああっ！
ゴホッ ゴホッ！
砂嵐が もう少し続いていたら→
If the sandstorm continued
any longer,
ここが私たちの
お墓になってたわよ。
this would have
become our grave.
(リー)何が起こるか
わからないのが魔の砂漠です！
You never know
what will happen next.
That's the Demon Desert!
さっさと二次試験通過と
いきましょう！
Let's get this Second Exam
over with.
そうね 中央塔は ここから
そう遠くないはずだし。
Right! The central tower
isn't far from here.
さあ レッツゴーです！
All right! Let's go!
What's the matter?
どうかしましたか？
何か忘れ物？
Did you forget something?
ああ 中央塔に行く前に
しなければならないことがある。
Yeah…
There's something we need to do
before we head for the central tower.
そうですね 僕にも決着を
つけたい相手がいました。
Yes.
There's someone I want
to settle things with too.
そういう方がいるんですね！
Do you have someone
like that too?
いや そういうことではない。
No, it's nothing like that.
それに何か問題が？
Is there something
the matter with them?
ちゃんと２本揃ってるし。
We have two scrolls.
実は…。
Actually…
– What?!
(リー/テンテン)え～っ!?
They're both "Heaven" scrolls.
２本とも天の書だ。
なぜなんです!?
How could you?!
なぜ そんな大事なことを
今まで秘密にしていたんですか!?
Why did you keep something
so important a secret?!
別に秘密にしていたわけではない。
I didn't intend to
keep it a secret.
ただ いろいろあって
話すチャンスがなかっただけだ。
It's just that things happened and
I didn't have a chance to tell you.
それって
何の言い訳にもなってないし。
That's a really bad excuse…
こうなったら 気をとりなおして→
Well, we'll just have to recoup
and obtain an "Earth" scroll somehow.
地の書の巻き物を
手に入れるしかありませんね。
ん？
Byakugan!
白眼！
あっちだ。
Over that way!
ちょっと待ってください！
ったくもう！
Please wait!
Oh, come on!
えっ え～!? あんな
疲れきったような人から→
H-Hey! You're going to take
a scroll from someone
who's ready to drop
from exhaustion?!
巻き物を奪うつもりですか？
そんな卑怯者がやるようなことは
断じてできません！
We can't do something
so cowardly!
Don't jump to conclusions!
早とちりするな！
We can't ignore someone
in distress.
行き倒れを
放ってはおけないだろう。
That's right!
そうね！ 大体 ネジが そんな
酷いことするわけないでしょ。
Neji would never stoop
to such a dirty trick.
アハハ… 当然 そんなふうには
思っていませんが。
Of course not! The thought
never crossed my mind…
(ネジ)どうした？ 何かあったのか？
Did something happen?
風影様が… 我愛羅様が
何者かに襲われているんです。
It's Lord Kazekage!
Someone is attacking Lord Gaara!
我愛羅が？
Gaara?!
《あと少しだ》
Just a little longer.
No one will come to help us.
今回 オープニングを飾るのは
小林幸子さんです。
Negative thoughts aren't good!
モクハチは もとより→
No matter how long
we wait,
reinforcements from
the Sand won't come!
テレビでは初めて披露する
特別のステージです。
Again with those
negative thoughts!
Would you still say that
if you knew
that the one attacking us
is from the Sand?
Are you serious?!
Next time on Naru